<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R/Pharma conferences and events | R/Pharma</title>
    <link>/event/</link>
      <atom:link href="/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>R/Pharma conferences and events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© R/Pharma 2025</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hu7da996d8ce7178f65929875a2132de7e_457633_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>R/Pharma conferences and events</title>
      <link>/event/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2023/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post was &lt;a href=&#34;https://rviews.rstudio.com/2018/10/03/some-thoughts-on-r-pharma-2018/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;originally shared on R/Views&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s no secret that there are few industries more competitive than the pharmaceutical
industry. Big money placed on long-shot bets for block-buster drugs where being
first makes all the difference means a constant struggle to gain a competitive edge.
So, you might find it surprising that the inaugural R / Pharma Conference held this
past August on the Harvard campus in a very classy auditorium was all about collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some might also find it surprising that data scientists from competitive companies
would gather to share information, but this is quite common. I have seen it before
in other competitive industries, for example in IEEE-led standards initiatives,
where engineers gather to forge a common technology. Not only is there the human
need to share and learn from peers (and also brag a little), there is a larger
force at play: a kind of market clearing operation where experts gather to gain
as much of an advantage as they can by ensuring that no easily exploitable
arbitrage opportunities remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a surprise, though (and I think a source of general amusement as the
conference proceeded), that nearly every talk seemed to be about Shiny.
Looking back, it is clear that it should not have been: 49% of the abstracts
explicitly mention Shiny. This word cloud was built from the abstract submissions.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-abstract-wordcloud&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Abstract wordcloud.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/rinpharma2019/figure1_hu10063e8ada7dc1135792ffdd8546e71f_109316_9cfacf5ce93636aa9ca87a48e2721393.png 400w,
               /event/rinpharma2019/figure1_hu10063e8ada7dc1135792ffdd8546e71f_109316_9943bcbee854289c4640ea964dbfce02.png 760w,
               /event/rinpharma2019/figure1_hu10063e8ada7dc1135792ffdd8546e71f_109316_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_2.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/event/rinpharma2019/figure1_hu10063e8ada7dc1135792ffdd8546e71f_109316_9cfacf5ce93636aa9ca87a48e2721393.png&#34;
               width=&#34;526&#34;
               height=&#34;526&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Abstract wordcloud.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiny is basically a technology for sharing complex information across multiple
organizations and stakeholders with different skill sets. Shiny, too, is all
about collaboration. For a look into the large, production-grade Shiny app,
bioWARP, see Sebastian Wolf’s recent post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other major themes addressed at the conference were: reproducible research,
package administration, scaling R for production, and using R in a regulatory
environment. This last theme was underscored by a strong FDA presence.
Lilliam Rosario from the FDA Center for Drug Evaluation &amp;amp; Research delivered
the opening keynote, in which she addressed the regulatory role of CDER and
the use of R. FDA speaker Mat Souktup spoke about the need to transcend the
compartmentalized culture common in medical research, and how open-source tools
are helpful in working towards this goal. He explicitly noted along the way
that the FDA does not specify what software may be used. The third FDA speaker,
Paul Schuette, filled in some details associated with topics raised by Rosario
and talked about the use of R and Shiny at CDER. Along these same lines,
Andy Nicholls from GSK conducted a well-attended and very informative workshop
on The Challenges of Validating R. You can find Andy’s slides here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other keynote speakers were Max Kuhn, who talked about Modeling in the tidyverse
(slides here); Joe Cheng, who described how to use Shiny responsibly in pharma
(slides here); and Michael Lawrence, who spoke about enabling open-source
analytics in the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My very biased impression was that R / Pharma was an unqualified success at
accomplishing the major objectives of bringing together data scientists and
statisticians working in the Pharmaceutical industry, and of presenting a high
quality program that explored several issues relating to the production use of
R in a regulatory environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following chart shows that representatives from quite a few pharmaceutical
companies attended in spite of organization problems that artificially limited
the overall number of attendees to about 140.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-attendees&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;Attendees.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/rinpharma2019/attendees_huc4a7e3a141a5b09654f3159707768a40_64003_0c0ffeebcbcee0a2f1941b91d14fd4fe.png 400w,
               /event/rinpharma2019/attendees_huc4a7e3a141a5b09654f3159707768a40_64003_c90c42ab05c342b5a1981b20458d433d.png 760w,
               /event/rinpharma2019/attendees_huc4a7e3a141a5b09654f3159707768a40_64003_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_2.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/event/rinpharma2019/attendees_huc4a7e3a141a5b09654f3159707768a40_64003_0c0ffeebcbcee0a2f1941b91d14fd4fe.png&#34;
               width=&#34;745&#34;
               height=&#34;730&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Attendees.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Conference</title>
      <link>/event/rinpharma2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/rinpharma2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The R / Pharma conference began as grass-roots initiative led by data scientists working in
the pharmaceutical industry to promote the use of R in Pharma, and to establish and share
best practices. The founding members organized the project as an R Consortium working
group, and undertook the ambitious task of launching an annual conference envisioned as a
relatively small, collegial, industry-oriented event with a strong scientific program.&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-rpharma-2018-participants&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img alt=&#34;R/Pharma 2018 participants.&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/rinpharma2018/figure1_hu17cd93a4fa8249ad94fe6954e536475c_152325_f8b2389fd092978bcf7bcd12ae67e776.png 400w,
               /event/rinpharma2018/figure1_hu17cd93a4fa8249ad94fe6954e536475c_152325_b09a6c23317c87ce87327c703ff534c4.png 760w,
               /event/rinpharma2018/figure1_hu17cd93a4fa8249ad94fe6954e536475c_152325_1200x1200_fit_lanczos_2.png 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;/event/rinpharma2018/figure1_hu17cd93a4fa8249ad94fe6954e536475c_152325_f8b2389fd092978bcf7bcd12ae67e776.png&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;469&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      R/Pharma 2018 participants.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynotes (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2SdvMNd&#34;&gt;https://bit.ly/2SdvMNd&lt;/a&gt;) were presented by Lilliam Rosario of the FDA’s
Center for Drug Evaluation and Research, Michael Lawrence Genentech/Roche and the R
Core Group, and Max Kuhn and Joe Cheng from RStudio.
Over forty-five talks and workshops were delivered with topics ranging from reproducible research, regulatory constraints and considerations, and package administration
to scaling R for production. A considerable number of talks emphasized the development
of production-grade Shiny applications. Although considerably larger than most of the
Shiny applications developed, Roche’s 500,000 line application, which was presented at
the conference and subsequently written up in a post (&lt;a href=&#34;https://bit.ly/2NeXKFJ),&#34;&gt;https://bit.ly/2NeXKFJ),&lt;/a&gt; reflects a
common use case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizing-committee&#34;&gt;Organizing Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melvin Munsaka - AbbVie; Bella Fang and Min Lee - Amgen; Eric Nantz - Eli Lilly; Elena
Rantou and Paul Schuette - FDA; Elizabeth Hess - Harvard; James Black, Reinhold Koch,
and Michael Lawrence - Genentech / Roche; Edward Louzier - Merck; Michael Blanks -
PPD; Phil Bowsher - RStudio; and Harvey Lieberman - Sanofi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;program-committee&#34;&gt;Program Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-chairs for the program committee were Bella Feng - Amgen, John Sims - Pfizer, and Ryan
Benz - SocalBioinformatics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Program committee leads included: Melvin Munsaka - AbbVie; Robert Engle - Biogen;
Elena Rantou and Paul Schuette - FDA; Elizabeth Hess - Harvard University; James Black
and Reinhold Koch - Genentech/Roche; Paulo Bargo - Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson; Eric Nantz - Eli
Lilly; Edward Lauzier - Merck; Xiao Ni- Novartis; Thomas Tensfeldt - Pfizer; and Harvey
Lieberman - Sanofi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
