<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | R/Pharma</title>
    <link>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© R/Pharma 2021</copyright>
    <image>
      <url>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/media/logo_hu7da996d8ce7178f65929875a2132de7e_457633_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently asked questions</title>
      <link>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#how-do-i-get-a-ticket-for-2021&#34;&gt;How do I get a ticket for 2021?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-mission-and-history-of-rpharma&#34;&gt;What is the mission and history of R/Pharma?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#whats-your-policy-on-creating-a-safe-place-for-attendees&#34;&gt;What’s your policy on creating a safe place for attendees?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;Terms and conditions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;faq&#34;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick guide to some the important questions we are often asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-get-a-ticket-for-2021&#34;&gt;How do I get a ticket for 2021?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R/Pharma is a free event put on by volunteers with the generosity of Pharma
companies and Harvard University. Tickets are now available at this link.
After registering for a ticket please check our blog and twitter feed
regularly for additional details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-the-mission-and-history-of-rpharma&#34;&gt;What is the mission and history of R/Pharma?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check out our &lt;a href=&#34;https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/thewhy/&#34;&gt;first blog post&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-your-policy-on-creating-a-safe-place-for-attendees&#34;&gt;What’s your policy on creating a safe place for attendees?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R/Pharma is dedicated to providing a harassment-free conference experience
for everyone regardless of gender, sexual orientation, disability or any
feature that distinguishes human beings. For more information, please
see the R Consortium code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;terms-and-conditions&#34;&gt;Terms and conditions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Terms and conditions statement can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/terms/&#34;&gt;terms and conditions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get your R/Pharma 2020 Merch</title>
      <link>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/2020-10-01-merch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/2020-10-01-merch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R/Pharma 2021 hopes to continue our tradition of diversity scholarships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The R/Pharma ISC Working Group (through the R Consortium) values diversity and
is focused on helping to encourage and support diversity and inclusion in the R/Pharma Community.
To help fund the grants, we plan to use the proceeds from the conference
merchandise found on our store here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bonfire.com/store/r-in-pharma/&#34;&gt;https://www.bonfire.com/store/r-in-pharma/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The store will remain open until Sunday, 18th October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long run, we hope that the R/Pharma conference participants reflect
the full diversity of the world around us. We believe in building on-ramps
so that people from diverse backgrounds can learn R, build their knowledge,
and then contribute back to the pharma community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The what and the why for R/Pharma</title>
      <link>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/thewhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://epijim.github.io/r-pharma/post/thewhy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details class=&#34;toc-inpage d-print-none  &#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;font-weight-bold&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By design, R / Pharma is deliberately a smaller conference in terms of attendance
in order to encourage maximum opportunities for direct interaction with speakers.
In 2018 and 2019 the conference was held in the Tsai Auditorium at the
Center for Government and International Studies, Harvard University and capped at
150 attendees. The conference was run as a free event. Invitations were based on
committee membership and advisory support, speaker acceptance, academic/student and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conference has been run with single track consisting of keynotes from renowned
industry practitioners to key R developers to leading academics. In addition
there were a number of pre-conference workshops and full-length presentations as
well as a number of shorter, highly-energetic lightning talks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 2020 we are taking a hiatus from holding the meeting at Harvard and
will be running a virtual conference. More details will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our entire event is a community-lead effort and 100% volunteer run. The
event is vendor neutral and very much an academic conference. Harvard has been very helpful in hosting the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R/Pharma is an (ISC working group)[https://www.r-consortium.org/projects/isc-working-groups]
under the R Consortium. The conference is a relatively small, scientifically &amp;amp;
industry oriented, collegial event focused on the use of R in the development of
pharmaceuticals. The conference covers topics including reproducible research,
regulatory compliance and validation, safety monitoring, clinical trials, drug
discovery, research &amp;amp; development, PK/PD/pharmacometrics, genomics, diagnostics,
immunogenicity and more. All are discussed within the context of using R as a
primary tool within the drug development process. The conference showcases
the current use of R that is helping to drive biomedical research, drug discovery
&amp;amp; development, and clinical initiatives. (Note that topics related to the use of
R in hospitals/clinics for patient care by clinicians, doctors, and
researchers is the focus of
(R/Medicine)[https://events.linuxfoundation.org/r-medicine/].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R/Pharma is dedicated to providing a harassment-free conference experience for
everyone regardless of gender, sexual orientation, disability or any feature that
distinguishes human beings. For more information, please see the R Consortium
code of conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
